Antoine Soetewey

antoinesoetewey.com

Summary

I am a PhD student in statistics at UCLouvain in Belgium, within the Institute of Statistics, Biostatistics and Actuarial Sciences. My research interests focus on biostatistical procedures applied to cancer patients.

In parallel with my doctoral thesis, I am teaching assistant for several courses in statistics and probability at bachelor and master's level and I provide trainings and workshops in data science, statistics and R programming for UCLouvain's technology platform for Statistical Methodology and Computing Service.

In my spare time, I write about statistics and code in R via my blog statsandr.com.

Education

2017 - Precent

2015 - 2016

2017 – 1 Tesent	ind in statistics - Octouvain, beigium
	- Thesis: Life and health actuarial pricing: a biostatistics approach (supervisors: Prof.
	Catherine Legrand and Prof. Michel Denuit)
	- All publications, posters and talks available at antoinesoetewey.com/research

MSc in econometrics & operations research – Maastricht University, Netherlands
Thesis: Combining professional and survey forecasts for macroeconomic data (supervisor: Prof. Nalan Basturk)

2013 – 2015 **MSc in economics** – KULeuven, Belgium

PhD in statistics - IICI ouvain Relaium

- Thesis: Negativity bias and framing effect in charity donations: a field experiment (supervisor: Prof. Jo Swinnen)

Aug – Sep 2014 Faculty exchange – University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign, USA

Teaching and consulting experience

2017 – Present **Teaching assistant in statistics** – UCLouvain, Belgium

- See all courses at antoinesoetewey.com/teaching

2018 - Present Consultant and instructor in statistics & R programming - SMCS & easystat.be

- Statistical and data analysis consulting for professionals, academics and students
- Instructor for UCL ouvain's university certificates "Introduction to data analysis with ${\bf R}$ ", "Junior data analyst" and "Practice of statistics with ${\bf R}$ "

Industry experience

2016 – 2017 Data scientist – Business & Decision, Belgium

- Involved in several projects focusing on data science and data visualization
- 2015 European public affairs intern BNP Paribas, Belgium
- 2015 Audit intern Deloitte, Luxembourg

Leadership experience

2017 – Present International tennis chair umpire – International Tennis Federation

- Work regularly as a chair or line umpire on major tennis events across the world

2016 – Present Committee member – Association Francophone de Tennis, Belgium

Technical skills & languages

Software

- See all projects at antoinesoetewey.com/software

Languages

- French (native), English (fluent), Dutch (intermediate)